<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>News and Status</title>
    <author email="tma@netspace.net.au">Tim Anderson</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="News and Status">
      <p>
        This document contains the latest news and status regarding the
        OpenJMS project.
      </p>

      <subsection name="June ??, 2006 - OpenJMS 0.7.7-beta-1 released">
        <p>
          See the <a href="release-notes.html">Release Notes</a> for more
          details.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="December 26, 2005 - OpenJMS 0.7.7-alpha-3 released">
        <p>
          See the <a href="release-notes.html">Release Notes</a> for more
          details.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="June 17, 2005 - OpenJMS 0.7.7-alpha-1 released">
        <p>
          This represents the first release of the OpenJMS 0.7.7 codebase.
        </p>
        <p>
          See the <a href="release-notes.html">Release Notes</a> for more
          details.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="May 7, 2004 - OpenJMS 0.7.6.1 released">
        <p>
          This is a maintenance release for OpenJMS 0.7.6.
        </p>
        <p>
          See the <a href="changes-report.html#0.7.6.1">Changes Report</a>
          for a complete list of the changes in 0.7.6.1
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="January 29, 2004 - OpenJMS 0.7.6 released">
        <p>
          See the <a href="changes-report.html#0.7.6">Changes Report</a>
          for a complete list of the changes in 0.7.6.
        </p>
        <p>
          <strong>Note:</strong> the 0.7.6 release will be the last release to
          support the JDBM database.
          There are no plans to provide a tool to migrate data from a JDBM
          database to a JDBC database.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="November 2, 2003 - OpenJMS 0.7.6 RC3 released">
        <p>
          This fixes the following bugs in the RC2 release:
          <ul>
            <li>819212 - Failed to delete the message with id=ID:..</li>
            <li>823331 - Can't acknowledge message after republishing</li>
            <li>827545 - non-persistent msgs to non durable subscriber not
                expiring</li>
            <li>826378 - errors in oracle table script</li>
            <li>816895 - Exception in purgeMessages.</li>
            <li>831535 - Cannot connect to DB after idle several hours.</li>
            <li>832157 - Remove LeaseManagerConfiguration.</li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="September 26, 2003 - OpenJMS 0.7.6 RC2 released">
        <p>
          This fixes a number of bugs in the RC1 release:
          <ul>
            <li>796633 - openjms.bat script terminates command prompt</li>
            <li>797284 - http connector: Failed to process request</li>
            <li>806378 - HTTPS connector configuration documentation
                incomplete</li>
            <li>806377 - HTTPS connector shouldn't convert host names</li>
            <li>810972 - sh scripts are in windows format</li>
            <li>811702 - Can administratively remove active durable consumer
            </li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="August 26, 2003 - OpenJMS 0.7.6 RC1 released">
        <p>
          This is the first release to include authentication support.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="May 21, 2003 - JMS CTS moves to a new home">
        <p>
         The Java Message Service Compliance Test Suite (JMS CTS),
         been spun out into a new project, at
         <a href="http://jmscts.sourceforge.net">
           http://jmscts.sourceforge.net
         </a><br/>
         Its license has also been changed to the Exolab Project open source
         license.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="May 10, 2003 - OpenJMS 0.7.5 is released!">
        <p>
          This contains a few cosmetic changes since the 0.7.5 RC1 release.
          See the <a href="changes-report.html#0.7.5">Changes Report</a>
          for a complete list of the changes in 0.7.5.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="April 15, 2003 - OpenJMS 0.7.5 RC1 released">
        <p>
          We have managed to sort out most of the issues related to TCP, HTTP
          and HTTPS. OpenJMS also has improved realtime garbage collection for
          persistent messages so there is no need to schedule batch garbage
          collection.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="January 24, 2003 - OpenJMS 0.7.4 released!">
        <p>
          This version has substantial changes to the memory management and
          overall stability and performance of the OpenJMS server.
          It fixes bugs with the TCP and HTTP connector as well as a number of
          bugs with transacted sessions, QueueBrowser, and IntraVM support.
        </p>
        <p>
          See the <a href="changes-report.html#0.7.4">Changes Report</a>
          for a complete list of the changes in 0.7.4.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="November 15, 2002 - OpenJMS 0.7.3.1 released!">
        <p>
          This build fixes corrects a problem with the TCP connector introduced
          in the 0.7.3 release.
        </p>
        <p>
          This release fixes some problems with transacted sessions and the
          Queue messaging model. It also has a more efficient implementation
          of receive() and  resolves some outstanding issues with temporary
          destinations. Finally it provides a sample configuration file to
          install OpenJMS as a service using
          <a href="http://wrapper.sourceforge.net/doc/english/index.html">
          Wrapper.exe</a>
        </p>
        <p>
          See the <a href="changes-report.html#0.7.3.1">Changes Report</a>
          for a complete list of the changes in 0.7.3.1.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="February 01, 2002 - OpenJMS v0.7.2 is now available!">
        <p>
          The latest version once again includes a revamped configuration
          file, which is more coherent and simpler to use. To ease the
          conversion pain we have provided a utility to convert old
          configuration files to the new format.
        </p>
        <p>
          The new version of OpenJMS has fixed the intermittent bug with
          persistent messages and RDBMS databases. It also provides support for
          HTTP and HTTPS connectors to facilitate communication across
          interposing firewalls and NATs. Additionally, the OpenJMS server
          provides limited support for the configuration of multiple
          connectors, which could be used to provide both secure and non-secure
          access to the same server.
        </p>
        <p>
          Several critical JMS specification bugs have been resolved,
          in particular those related to durable subscribers, selectors,
          and connection factories. We have further developed the
          CTS (Compliance Test Suite), which now runs some 10000 tests on the
          OpenJMS server to ensure that we remain compliant with the
          specification. The CTS is not part of our open source offering but
          remains crucial to the product's quality assurance.
        </p>
        <p>
          To further automate our testing process we have released a soak test
          framework, based on Jakarta ANT, which can be used to automate
          end-to-end OpenJMS testing. The framework is used internally to test
          the numerous combinations of transports and databases. To start
          using the framework read the README file in the src/soak directory.
        </p>
        <p>
          In the next release we will be looking at improving the number of
          concurrent connections that a server can support as well as the
          throughput of persistent messages on RDBMS databases.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="September 27, 2001 - OpenJMS 0.7 released!">
        <p>
          OpenJMS v0.7 has increased performance through refactoring of
          key packages. It is now able to support large number of administered
          destinations and durable consumers (> 10000), with improved resource
          management and new services. SSL support has been added to the IPC
          connection using Sun Microsystems JSSE implementation.
          We have also successfully configured OpenJMS to run across the
          internet with interposing firewalls an NATs
          between the client and the server.
        </p>
        <p>
          OpenJMS is also more compliant to the JMS specification than ever
          before. Our JMS Compliance Test Suite (CTS), which is a new project,
          aims to exercise all aspects of the specification. We are currently
          on track to achieve 80-90% coverage with the next 4-5 weeks.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Jun 9, 2001 - OpenJMS 0.6 released">
        <p>
          OpenJMS v0.6 is a stable and reliable implementation of the
          JMS specifications. We have introduced in-memory and database based
          garbage collection, which helps maintain a small memory footprint.
          The latest version now supports the ExceptionListener facility and
          automatic client disconnection detection for both the RMI and MIPC
          protocols. In addition, the MIPC protocol is ideal to embed the
          OpenJMS client into an applet. This version has resolved
          many of the bug reports and has improved the server's persistent
          message throughput. Although, the extent of the changes does mean
          that we are no longer compatible with earlier versions of OpenJMS.
          In particular, this will effect users that have an existing database
          of persistent messages and want to upgrade to the latest version.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="November 11, 2000 - OpenJMS 0.5 released">
        <p>
          OpenJMS 0.5 is a feature complete implementation of Sun
          Microsystems' JMS 1.0.2 Specification excluding the XA application
          server facility support. We have improved the general reliability of
          the (IPC, RMI and IntraVM) servers. In addition, we have extended
          our RDBMS support by covering Sybase, Oracle, MySQL and Postgres.
          Selectors have stabilized and performance has improved. This
          version also supports Topic Hierarchy, part of the Application
          Server Facility specification, client-server flow control and queue
          browser. Finally, this version facilitates the deployment of JMS
          clients inside an Applet.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="September 13, 2000 - OpenJMS 0.4 is released">
        <p>
          OpenJMS v0.4 now includes full support for the SQL-92
          selectors, as outlined in the JMS 1.0.2 specifications. Through the
          use of <a href="http://castor.exolab.org">Castor</a>
          JDO, the persistency mechanism now supports both the JDBM and RDBMS
          adapters.
          OpenJMS should now be able to support all databases supported by
          <a href="http://castor.exolab.org">Castor</a>.
          Testing so far has only been conducted on Oracle 8i.1.6 and
          Sybase 12. The testharness has been significantly improved to run
          through and test all configurations of the OpenJMS server.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="July 18, 2000 - OpenJMS v0.3 is released">
        <p>
          This release doesn't include many more features over and above those
          introduced in 0.2.1. It improves the reliability of the TCP
          connector and general stability of the product. It also extends the
          test coverage of the JMS client. Finally, this release, includes all
          the code required to support SQL-92 selectors, as outlined in the JMS
          1.0.2 specifications (thanks to Tim Anderson).
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="June 23, 2000 - OpenJMS v0.2.1 is released">
        <p>
          This is an interim release that fixes some bugs in the 0.2 release,
          introduces a TCP/IP connector and improves the performance of
          persistent message delivery. It also supports TemporaryTopic and
          TemporaryQueue objects and extends the coverage of the test harness.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="June 1, 2000">
        <p>
          OpenJMS v0.2 is released.
          The release support both persistent and non-persistent delivery
          modes in addition to both point-to-point and publish-subscribe
          messaging models.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="March 28, 2000">
        <p>
          OpenJMS announced at the O'Reilly Java Conference.
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="March 1, 2000">
        <p>
          OpenJMS, an open source implementation of the JMS 1.0.2
          specifications is launched.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
